Arthur W. Row Papers MS090
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Arthur W. Row letters, periodicals, photographs and books, 1864 -- 1938; 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001; 8.4 Linear Feet
  - Manuscripts of AWR's writings, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005
    - Manuscript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00101 (Box 5)
    - Notebook with notes on "Plots and Playwrights", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00102 (Box 5)
    - Typescript, manuscript and annotated manuscript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00103 (Box 5)
    - Typescript, lightly annotated, of large portion of "Sarah the Divine", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00104 (Box 5)
    - Typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt headed "Sarah and the Critics", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00105 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages from "Sarah the Divine", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00106 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript, typescript and annotated typescript pages, mostly on Sarah Bernhardt, poem titled "London" by E.M. Fryer of Philadelphia, two British travel brochures, assorted clippings on theatre, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00107 (Box 5)
  - AWR's Bible, 1891; MS090.001.006.001 (Box 6)
  - The Miracle, staged by Max Reinhardt, 1924; MS090.001.007.001 (Box 7)
    Souvenir program of production directed by Morris Gest.
  - A. W. Row, scrapbook of actors, 1914 -- 1917; MS090.001.008.001 (Box 8)
    Newspaper clippings, letters, programs, and misc. memorabilia.
    Scrapbook; Row, A.W.
  - A. W. Row, scrapbook of actors and playbooks, 1911 -- 1913; MS090.001.009.001 (Box 9)
  - A. W. Row, scrapbook of actors and playbooks, 1930; MS090.001.010.001 (Box 10)
    Newspaper clippings, letters, programs, and misc. memorabilia, particularly of Randolph Churchill's tour of the U.S.
  - A. W. Row, news clippings and notes on Sarah Bernhardt, 1910 -- 1920; MS090.001.011.001 (Box 11)
    Notebooks, newspaper clippings, manuscript typed pages of his book, Sarah, the Divine, as well as writings about plays and acting, ca. 1910.
  - A. W. Row, scrapbook and clippings, 1920; MS090.001.012.001 (Box 12)
    Newspaper clippings of Sarah Bernhardt and programs from the Afternoon Theatre. This book previously belonged to MS075. Date is approximate
  - The dramatic works of William Shakespeare, 1864; MS090.001.013.001 (Box 13)
    Presented to AWR on his 18th birthday. Listed in the inventory of his books. William Collins, Queen's Printer, London: 1864.
  - Pieces of costumes; wig, spats, MS090.001.014.001 (Box 14)
    Pair of grey woolen felt spats with buckles. A balding grey (real hair) theatrical wig.
  - Grey boots worn by Mary Shaw, 1900; MS090.001.015.001 (Box 15)
    Worn by Mary Shaw in the Broadway production of Ben Hur.
    Shaw, Mary; Row, A.W.
  - Stage jewelery, MS090.001.016.001 (Box 16)
    Costume stage jewelery as listed in Row's inventory.
  - Shoe stretchers and flashlight, MS090.001.017.001 (Box 17)
    This set of shoe stretchers were found alongside the boots owned by Mary Shaw (see MS 090-015). The box also includes an old cigarette box with a Burgess snaplight flashlight, also found by the boots. No Date Available
  - Row's periodicals and inventory of collection, 1893 -- 1934; MS090.001.018
    - Dictionnaire Francais-Anglais, 1926; MS090.001.018.00001 (Box 18)
      Paris, Librairie Hatier; New York, Doubleday, Page & Co. By Charles Cestre.
    - Hawaiian Phrase Book 5th Ed., 1893; MS090.001.018.00002 (Box 18)
      Na huaolelo a me na olelo kikeke ma ka olelo Beritania, a me ka olelo Hawaii. Honolulu, Whitney & Roberts.
    - Notes from the Unstruck Music, (From the Gayan of Inayat Khan), 1926; MS090.001.018.00003 (Box 18)
      Southampton, Book depot for Sufi literature. 104 p.
    - Theta Delta Chi catalogues, 1917, 1922, MS090.001.018.00004 (Box 18)
    - Equity, Aug., 1933; MS090.001.018.00005 (Box 18)
    - Equity, Dec., 1934; MS090.001.018.00006 (Box 18)
    - Equity, Aug., 1928; MS090.001.018.00007 (Box 18)
    - Psychology, July, 1926; MS090.001.018.00008 (Box 18)
    - Psychology, Jan., 1926; MS090.001.018.00009 (Box 18)
    - Psychology, Aug., 1926; MS090.001.018.00010 (Box 18)
    - The School for Scandal, playscript, 1901; MS090.001.018.00011; Sheridan, Richard Brinsley (Box 18)
      A comedy in five acts by Richard Brinsley Sheridan as remodeled and rearranged by Augustin Daly. Samuel French publication. Two copies.
    - The Cherry Orchard, playscript, 1922; MS090.001.018.00012; Chekhov, Anton (Box 18)
      A comedy in four acts by Anton Tchekhoff(sic), English translation by Jenny Covan. The Moscow Art Theatre series of Russian Plays under the direction of Morris Gest.
    - The Brothers Karamazoff, playscript, 1923; MS090.001.018.00013; Dostoevsky, Fyodor (Box 18)
      Six scenes from the novel by Fyodor Dostoievsky(sic), English translation by Jenny Covan. The Moscow Art Theatre series of Russian Plays under the direction of Morris Gest.
    - Twelfth Night, playscript, n.d., MS090.001.018.00014; Shakespeare, William (Box 18)
      A comedy in five acts by William Shakspeare (sic). French's Standard Drama edition. No Date Available
    - Seventh Heaven, playscript, 1922; MS090.001.018.00015; Strong, Austin (Box 18)
      A play in three acts by Austin Strong. Samuel French edition.
    - Lady Windermere's Fan, playscript, 1893; MS090.001.018.00016; Wilde, Oscar (Box 18)
      A Play About a Good Woman in four acts by Oscar Wilde. French's Standard Library Edition.
    - Thy Will Be Done, playscript, 1923; MS090.001.018.00017 (Box 18)
      A drama by Gallarati-Scotti, English translation by Valerie Petri. The Eleonora Duse series of plays under the direction of Morris Gest.
    - The Return of the Prodigal, playscript, 1907; MS090.001.018.00018 (Box 18)
      A comedy in four acts by St. John Hankin. Samuel French edition.
    - School for Scandal, playscript, 1915; MS090.001.018.00019; Sheridan, Richard Brinsley (Box 18)
      A comedy in five acts by Richard Brinsley Sheridan. The William Warren Edition of Standard Plays. Walter H. Baker & Co., Boston.
    - The Lower Depths, playscript, 1922; MS090.001.018.00020; Gorky, Maxim (Box 18)
      A drama in fours acts by Maxim Gorky, english translation by Jenny Covan. The Moscow Art Theatre Series of Russian Plays under the direction of Morris Gest.
    - Romeo and Juliet, playscript, MS090.001.018.00021; Shakespeare, William (Box 18)
      A tragedy in five acts by William Shakspeare (sic). French's Standard Drama. No Date Available
    - Macbeth, playscript, MS090.001.018.00022; Shakespeare, William (Box 18)